Ashwin Shrestha

Phone: 9843729356 | Email: ashwinshres@gmail.com

Linked In Profile: https://np.linkedin.com/in/ashwin-shrestha-7545a2101

Website: https://ashwinshres.github.io

Address: Sahiyoginagar, Kathmandu, Bagmati, Nepal

OBJECTIVE

I am a result-oriented software developer/technical lead with five-year experience in mobile app development. I make it my goal to create software with the user in mind, creating applications with a useable and intuitive user interface experience.

I bring in the new and improved engineering processes and standards in the company, to help smooth the project workflows and answer questions and resolve issues brought forth by the engineering team members.

I also understand the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code. I am constantly striving to learn new technologies and look to ways to better myself in this rapidly changing industry.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer at Outcode Software

- October 2020 - Present

+ Responsibilities:

- Work with other team members to make client's idea into a reality.
- Design and define architecture of the system and bring the idea into reality
- Understand the project requirements clearly.
- Work closely with Project Managers and Project Owners in different project from the requirement gathering to end product delivery to the client.
- Discuss any technical challenges that might come affront while working on the project.
- Code the complex tasks of the project, review code of the developers and supervise trainees and junior developers.
- + Projects: Working on a platform for connecting entry-level jobs with job seekers

Engineering Manager (Contract) at Outcode Software

- July 2020 – October 2020

+ Responsibilities:

- Bring in the new and improved engineering processes and standards in the company, to help smooth the project workflows and answer questions and resolve issues brought forth by the engineering team members
- Work closely with Project Managers and Project Owners in different project from the requirement gathering to end product delivery to the client.

Engineering Manager at Insight Workshop

- February 2020 - September 2020

+ Responsibilities:

- Bring in the new and improved engineering processes and standards in the company, to help smooth the project workflows and answer questions and resolve issues brought forth by the engineering team members
- Work closely with Project Managers and Project Owners in different project from the requirement gathering to end product delivery to the client.
- Constant communication between Project owner and developers of the projects associated, to formulate, architect and carry out the project sprints, coding and UI/UX development.
- Provide consultancy and feedbacks to the client and Project owner on project architecture, development and planning.
- Code the complex tasks of the project, review code of the developers and supervise trainees and junior developers.
- + **Projects worked on:** Worked on two projects in swift 5 which involves Online learning platform and Social Gathering Platform which uses mainly MapKit, In-App purchase functionalities, PDFKit, Live Streaming using Kaltura platform, Core Graphics for animations and other normal iOS development using UIKit.

Senior iOS Developer at Insight Workshop

- December 2017 - February 2020

+ Responsibilities:

- Ensure the project are accurately estimated and delivered as scheduled.
- Actively contribute to the process of continual improvement, with regard to self, team and systems
- Project owner and Client communications as needed
- Project development
- Oversee the technologies, tools and techniques used within the team
- Perform 3rd line support as required
- + **Projects worked on :** Worked on 4 projects in swift 4+ and 5+ which includes a Social networking app with WebSocket implementation for Chat functionalities, an app for continuous location tracking rewarding user on basis of their location using MapKit and CoreLocation, a Health app using BLE technology to retrieve user's Health data like Blood pressure and show it in a chart representation, Core Graphics for animations and other normal iOS development using UIKit.

Associate Team Lead (IOS Development) at ebPearls Technology Pvt. Ltd.

- January 2017 – December 2017

+ Responsibilities:

- Be assistance in project estimation and requirement gathering
- Actively contribute to the process of continual improvement, with regard to self, team and systems
- Research on necessary functionalities needed in app.
- Project development
- Perform 3rd line support as required
- + **Projects worked on :** Worked on 3 projects in swift 3 which includes real time bidding system with WebSocket implementation, a Crew management app with real time user tracking and video/ audio call functionality with WebRTC and PushKit and Core Graphics for animations and other normal iOS development using UIKit.

Software developer (IOS Development) at ebPearls Technology Pvt. Ltd.

- September 2015 – December 2016

+ Responsibilities:

- Work with other team members to make client's idea into a reality.
- Work with backend developers for good communication and api integration.
- Understand the project requirements clearly.
- Generate queries in case there is any confusion in understanding the project.
- Discuss any technical challenges that might come affront while working on the project.
- Conduct first hand testing of the project tasks before submitting the tasks to the team lead.
- + **Projects:** Worked on Design app where app allows the user to personalise a contemporary urban designer range of invites including an RSVP tracker to ensure user's event guest list is taken care of. User can also custom design their own artwork, cards, quotes, prints and tram scrolls to send digitally or direct to the printers to print on card and/or canvas.

SKILLS

- **Domain Knowledge:** iOS application development
- Language Languages: Swift, Objective-C, C
- Database and Data Persistence: CoreData, User-defaults, Keychain, SQLite, Realm, Property Lists, FileManager
- Tools: Xcode, Git, Sketch
- Others: Apple developer account certificate generation, App-store app release
- iOS Specifics: MapKit and CoreLocation, In-App Purchase, CoreGraphics, Pushkit, SwiftUI
- Architecture: MVVM with Coordinator, MVC, MVP
- Soft Skill: Interpersonal expertise, Team work, Project Analysis. Project Estimation, Client Communication

EDUCATION

Kathmandu University 2011-2015

Bachelor of Computer Engineering.

Orchid Public Higher Secondary School 2009-2011

HSEB in Science Faculty

Siddhartha Shishu Sadan 1998-2009

SLC

FREELANCED-PROJECTS

• My freelanced projects are available in my website.

ACHIEVEMENT AND ACTIVITIES

- **Re-Nepal Hackathon 2015:** 1st runner up in Hackathon organized by Kathmandu Engineering College.
- LTSP Help Nepal: Volunteer for LTSP system deployment at at Saptari, Gaighat and Sunsari. (Year 2014), Salyan. (Year 2015)
- K.U. I.T. Meet 2014: Human Recourse Management for the I.T. Meet.

REFRENCES

Available upon request